Before we jump into the data analysis process,
在我们开始数据分析之前
let's talk about some of the kinds of problems you might solve as a data analyst.
先来谈谈数据分析师可能要解决的一些问题
When many people hear the term data analyst,
许多人一听到数据分析师这个词
they picture someone who works at a tech company and probably in Silicon Valley.
就会想到在科技公司工作的人 工作地点可能是在硅谷
Many data analysts do in fact work at tech companies.
许多数据分析师的确在科技公司工作
For example, Netflix uses data analysis to
比如 Netflix 使用数据分析
provide personalized movie recommendations for its users.
为用户提供个性化电影推荐服务
Facebook uses it in its news feed ranking algorithm.
Facebook 将数据分析应用到新闻推送排行算法中
And OkCupid uses it to predict which people are likely to be good romantic matches.
OkCupid 用数据分析来预测什么人有可能成为好伴侣
In addition to building these kinds of systems,
除了打造这些系统外
many companies also use data analysis to
许多公司还会用数据分析
publish papers or write blog posts about their findings.
将自己的发现发表成论文或撰写博文
For example, Facebook has studied the ideological diversity of people's political posts.
比如 Facebook 研究了人们政治文章的意识形态多样性
They found that when posts appear on
发现如果新闻推送里的文章
people's news feed written from a different perspective,
与用户所持角度不同
users are less likely to click on those posts.
用户点进去看的可能性就会小些
OkCupid wrote a blog post about
OkCupid 撰写了博文
what are the best questions to ask someone on a first date.
讲述了首次约会最适宜问对方的问题
Did you know that long term couples are very likely
你知道吗？
to agree about whether they like horror movies?
长期伴侣很可能会对恐怖电影有共同的喜好
Data analysts don't just work at tech companies though.
但数据分析师不仅仅在科技公司工作
Wal-Mart looks through their purchase records and people's posts on
沃尔玛通过观察购买记录
social media in order to figure out what to stock in their stores.
以及人们在社交媒体上发布的内容 来判断要为商店存什么货
Apparently, Strawberry Pop-Tarts are more likely to sell right before a hurricane.
显然 在飓风到来之前 草莓味的 Pop-Tarts 售出的可能性更大
Bill James is famous for applying data analysis to baseball.
Bill James 因将数据分析应用到棒球领域而出名
He used it to understand who the top performers
他用数据来分析谁的表现最好
are and how to best predict future performance.
并找出预测未来表现的最佳方法
And pharmaceutical companies have started to use machine learning to
制药公司也开始用机器学习
predict which chemical compounds are most likely to make effective drugs.
来预测什么化合物最有可能制成高效药物
Using this, they can make better decisions about which compounds are
利用机器学习 他们能够更好地做出决策
likely to be a good use of the resources involved in running a clinical trial.
决定在进行临床试验时 什么化合物将成为更好的可用资源
If you'd like to learn more about any of these applications,
如果你对上述应用有兴趣
check out the links in the instructor notes.
可以查看讲师注释里的链接